The death of Mona Dearly wasn't so much a whodunnit, as a who didn't.
Drowning Mona is a comedy, crime, mystery film directed by Nick Gomez.
The recently deceased Mona Dearly was many things: an abusive wife, a
domineering mother, a loud-mouthed neighbor and a violent malcontent.
So when her car and corpse are discovered in the Hudson River, police Chief
Wyatt Rash immediately suspects murder rather than an accident.
But, since the whole community of Verplanck, N.Y., shares a deep hatred for this unceasingly
spiteful woman, Rash finds his murder investigation overwhelmed with potential suspects.
Chief Wyatt Rash, played by Danny DeVito.
Mona Dearly, played by Bette Midler.
Ellen Rash, played by Neve Campbell.
Rona Mace, played by Jamie Lee Curtis.
Bobby Calzone, played by Casey Affleck.
Phil Dearly, played by William Fichtner.
Drowning Mona is a 2000 American crime comedy film starring Danny DeVito as Wyatt Rash, a local police chief from Verplanck, New York, who investigates the mysterious death of Mona
Dearly (Bette Midler), a spiteful, hard-drinking, loud-mouthed, abusive woman, hated by all who knew her, who drove her son's car off a cliff and drowned in a river.
The film received negative reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of investigation, suspicion, remake, murder, death.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.